Alexander Musayev

Full stack web developer

Location: Saint-Petersburg, Russia **GitHub:** https://github.com/dreikanter

Email: alex@musayev.com
LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/alexmusayev
Detailed CV: musayev.com
Languages: Fluent English and native Russian

About me

I have 15 years of experience in software development, including 5 years working remotely. Love to build robust and convenient tools that help my clients to save time, reduce business costs and transform complex to simple. As a remote developer, I value transparent communication and workflows. I can work independently or join a team. I have experience in leading a small development team as well.

Skills and Technologies

Primary languages: Ruby (Rails, dry-rb, Minitest, Sidekiq), **JavaScript** (React, Redux)

Web: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, BEM, Webpack, countless front-end frameworks and libs

DB and NoSQL: PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, Redis, ElasticSearch

Tools: Git (preferred version control), Rubocop, Reek, ESLint, stylelint

Server infrastructure: Linux, Ansible, AWS, Logstash, nginx

Recent Experience

2015–2019: Full stack developer, architect at PassionDig Inc

Responsibilities: System design and features development for web applications. Customer requirements analysis, specs drafting and implementation planning. Interviewing and onboarding new developers, code reviews.

Achievements: I've built an MVP version for an in-person educational service from scratch. Implemented geo-location search engine with flexible ranking logic. Created domain-specific web analytics backend for marketing team. Integrated third-party services, including Google Maps, Stripe, PayPal, Twitter, Facebook, helpdesk software with single sign-on capability, etc. Automated provisioning and deployment workflows. Created UI style guide based on custom reusable React component. Improved Rails application performance. Significantly reduced AWS operational costs for a SAAS infrastructure.

1/2 Last update: 2019/06/04

2014–2017: **Full stack developer** at UpWork

Participated in multiple projects as a full-stack web developer. My responsibilities included features development and performance optimization for Rails apps, payment services and social API integration, system automation, etc. Got <u>5 stars rating</u> with 100% job success.

2013–2015: **Architect** at Softin.co

Built an application licensing API. Prototyped a project management web service. Performed UX design and art direction for a mobile game project.

2012–2013: Senior software developer at Luxoft (Hewlett Packard)

Participated in WebInspect project development, an OWASP-based web app vulnerability scanner. New features implementation, UI i18n, technical documentation, interviewing and onboarding new developers. C#/.NET, WinForms (MVVM), WPF, Microsoft SQL Server.

Personal projects

Most of my personal projects are open source (https://github.com/dreikanter). There are tools for system automation, text processing, web content management, Google Chrome extensions, etc. Here are some examples:

Freefeed Feeder (https://frf.im) — an automated content publishing service built for FreeFeed.net social network. In production since 2017.

boodka (https://github.com/dreikanter/boodka) — sugar-free personal budget calculator. An experimental project, inspired by the lack of multi-currency support in YNAB.

public-static (https://github.com/dreikanter/public-static) — a static website builder that I've been using for a personal blog.

Education

M. Sc. (2004), St. Petersburg State University of Airspace Instrumentation (SUAI) Department of Automatic Control Systems. Specialty: Automatic Control and Information Processing Systems.

Postgrad (2008), St. Petersburg Institute for Informatics and Automation of the Russian Academy of Sciences (SPIIRAS). Specialty: Mathematical and Software Support of Computers, Complex Systems, and Networks.

Multiple certificates on system analysis, software architecture and UX design. UpWork and Smarterer.com tests on Python, Ruby, Ruby on Rails (master level).

There are more details on my working experience at <u>musayev.com</u>

2/2 Last update: 2019/06/04